uh why should you have a proton mail
account so again if you are here for the
beginner boost then you I'm assuming you
don't have strong preferences with
regard to
email and I'm going to over I'm going to
tell you at least for the beginner boost
what I've been doing with people since
2013 I've been helping people set up you
know their initial accounts a lot of
them were young people so they didn't
even have an account and that meant
Consulting with their parents and stuff
like that so the reasons are not
completely obvious um so first of all
here is the service the service is
proton mail uh
prme uh you can create a free account
over here and I'm not going to go
through all the steps because the steps
will inevitably change from the time
that I make this video the time you're
doing it but just make a free account
and protl has a tremendously good um uh
application for the phone uh protl has
got a really really great encrypted API
you can actually use it this is a more
advanced concept but you can actually
they have their own SMTP localized mail
server that you can send to uh if you
want to use you know crazy command line
mail tools such as mut which you may not
have even considered using we're not
going to cover that in the Boost the
point is proton mail is a very Advanced
male service provider um they have
accounts in Switzerland they they they
they strongly strongly
prioritize
privacy um they have given up the uh
email addresses of activists in France
before uh when required to by law so
it's not completely immune if you want
to be that level of hacker you might
want to look for uh two to I mean
there's two to know there's a bunch of
other service providers but proton male
in general is a really um strong now to
pull disclosure I have been a Visionary
supporter of proton male since almost
when they came out which is like some
four year five years ago um I also use
protonvpn uh which comes with your
account um and there's a number of
reasons to use it these are the kind of
things that Google would never even
dream of giving you uh proton mail in
many ways in many respects is the polar
opposite uh in terms of corporate
priorities from Google and I don't want
to get into a rant about what I think
about Google versus protl um I just
think that if you are going to have a
email provider you should use one that
encrypts your email in a way that they
cannot even read it um and you can have
access to that email as well you can
also send encrypted email to other
people uh who have Protime accounts or
others um you can even send it to people
who don't have prot time mail accounts
they can click on it and they can get
see it I believe that email is one of
the fundamental things that
demands uh privacy considerations even
though I'm a very public figure um I
personally am very much an advocate for
privacy and that allows for that protl
does allow for that whereas Google and
Gmail do not um I do make another video
about why you need a Gmail account but
the reason to have a Gmail account is
separate from the reason to have a
proton mail account for example proton
mail does not allow um multiple email
addresses to be associated with a single
you have to pay extra and each one has
to be individually configured as opposed
to Gmail which you just add a plus to
the end and all of it goes to the same
email address which allows you to use
the same email for multiple account
setups that all comes to the same one
and then you can forward your email from
Gmail to proton mail and it will arrive
for the stuff that you care about and it
all it all lands in your in your inbox
and then you have the option of of not
doing that if you don't want to so you
use Gmail for all of your account setups
that need to have some random email
address you never put anything private
in your Gmail account of course um and
then you you save protom as your primary
mechanism for authenticating to more
important services such as um you know
name cheap and other places where you
would use a DNS address you want to you
really want a very very very secure
email server for that and that's what
prown mail is good for again I'm not
being paid by them I just really believe
in them I've been financially supporting
them for some time and and and I
encourage you to do the same we need
more Choice out in the world and if
nothing more we need to reward those
companies which are rewarding a focus on
privacy whether or not we are public
figures we need to reward that so
strongly encourage you get to Pro
account and if you if I was mentoring
you that would be a requirement